Guide to the Balmori Associates Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Project Records, 1941-2014; 1987-2014; Series I
  - St. Louis Riverfront, 2001-2006
    - 06 Powerpoint, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 11 RFP, 2005 February (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 01 Design data and research
      - Ice rinks, 2006 January (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Mississippi River, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - River (general), 2005 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Energy, 2005 May (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Wildlife, 2005 August (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Greenway, 2005 April (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Plants, 2005 July (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Bicycles, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Precedents, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Materials, 2005 August (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Bridges, 2005 August-December (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Design ideas, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Saarinen archives, 2005 July (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - History, 2005 July (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - Arch research, 2005 June (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - Arch competition, 2005 November-December (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Eads Bridge, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Bridge reuse, Circa 2005 (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Arch steps, Circa 2005 (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - Maps, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Publicity, 2005 April-September (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Electronic records
  - Bilbao projects, 1993-2012
    - General project records, 2004-2011
      - Budget, 2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Administrative, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Contracts, 2007-2009 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Diagrams, 2004-2007, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Drawings, Undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Images, 2007-2008, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Publicity, Undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Abandoibarra Master Plan, 1993-2006
      2012 marks the completion of Balmori Associates' Master Plan for Abandoibarra. For the past twenty years, Bilbao has reinvented itself by regenerating important sections of the city affected by the industrial crisis of the 1980's. One of those former industrial areas is a derelict harbor in the center of Bilbao called Abandoibarra.
      The Abandoibarra Master Plan was drawn by Balmori Associates, Cesar Pelli and Eugenio Aguinaga in 1998 (winner of an international competition). Balmori Associates created park guidelines and designed all open space, streets, sidewalks and plazas, placing emphasis on expanding the amount of green space in the city and incorporating sustainable design practices. Two-thirds of the Master Plan area are dedicated to parks and open space.
      Today, what was once a high-speed roadway, has been turned into a boulevard with multiple pedestrian crossings and a light rail now connects the two main cultural centers of the development: Frank Gehry's Guggenheim Museum and the city's opera house. Running on wide swaths of green lawn, this rail line gives continuity to green space. For the river edge, Balmori proposed a linear park, Parque de la Ribera. This new promenade, no less than thirty meters in width, is treated as a longitudinal space at two levels. The half nearest to the water proposes the pier's rehabilitation, maintaining the existing dialogue between both shores. The inside half, which is located at the 6m level, concurs with the exterior of the Guggenheim Museum. In 2005 this section of the Master Plan received the Special Award 'Città d'Acqua' of the Biennale di Venezia for Best Project. In 2003, Balmori Associates was commissioned the designed of Plaza Euskadi and in 2007, together with RTN Architect, won an international competition to design Campa de los Ingleses Park also located in Abandoibarra.
      - Master Plan, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Administrative, 1993-2006
        - Project directory, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 2)
        - Traffic correspondence, 1995-1998, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
        - Client correspondence, 1993-2006, undated (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
        - Community response to master plan, 1997 Sep-Oct (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Contract, 1997-2003, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Design
        - Tram design, 1996 Oct, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
        - Design concept, 1997-1998, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
        - Drawings and sketches, 1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
        - Drawings, 2006 Mar, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
        - Planting plans, 1993, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
        - Master plan drawing, 2002 Dec, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - Design preparation, 1994-2002, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - Complete construction drawing set and specifications, 1998 Sep (Box 17)
      - Publicity, 1994-2005, undated
        - Publicity, 1994-2005, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - Magazines, 2000-2004 (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - Magazines, 2007-2012 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Electronic records
      - Images (slides, negatives), 1996-1998, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Plaza Euskadi, 2002-2011
      Plaza Euskadi connects the nineteenth century section of the city called "El Ensanche" to the new section of Bilbao, Deusto university campus, the Guggenheim Museum, and the Nervión River. The Plaza is a pivot, unifying diverse elements of the city. Apart from the Museum of Fine Arts and historic residential buildings, the plaza is surrounded by contemporary buildings such as university and library buildings, a shopping mall, a subway station, hotels, residential buildings, an office skyscraper, designed by different architects including Gehry, Moneo, Pelli, Siza, Krier, Legorreta, and Stern.
      Oval in form, the plaza has two forms of circulation: a tree-lined perimeter path for leisurely walks and sitting, and a dominant central path which brings the people from downtown to Abandoibarra to the Campa de los Ingleses Park, The Rivers, and the pedestrian bridge crossing the river to Deusto University and its neighborhoods.
      Three public park "pockets" hook onto the sides of the central path, which provide colorful and playful seating made from recycled rubber. Each pocket has a different character: an amphitheater section with reflection puddles, an ottoman seating section, and a "garden" section of flowering shrubs with a 100 year old Laegostremia tree.
      In 2008 the construction of the plaza was impacted by the economic downturn in Spain leading to a complete re-design. The final design cost was half of the original construction budget which required the removal of fountains, a more modest planting and grading scheme, and a shift in materials.
      - Administrative, 2002-2008
        - Project directory, Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, client, 2002-2008 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Contract, 1997-2008 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - First design, 2004-2009
        - Schematics, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Schematics, 2004-2006 and undated (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
        - Development, 2004-2006 and undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Conceptual, 2004-2009 and undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
        - Construction, Jul 2008 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Redesign, 2007-2009
        - Schematics, Sep 2009 - Oct 2009 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Planting, 2007 and undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Publicity, 2006-2011, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Campa de los Ingleses Park, 2006-2012
      Campa de los Ingleses Park designed by Balmori Associates with RTN Architect is the result of an international design competition (2007).
      The park flows from the Guggenheim Bilbao Museum, unifying the Abandoibarra area of Bilbao and the Nervión River. The Park's design was based on gracefully mediating for pedestrians a ten meter (33 feet) elevation difference between the city above and the Nervión River below. This was achieved with ramps, terraces, and topography, earthforms serving to control vistas and to allow for a café to be tucked under.
      Instead of an "Industrial Lawn", a "Freedom Lawn" was planted by introducing various grass species, clover and wildflowers that fixes nitrogen and reduces the need for pesticides. The paving designed by Balmori contains an additive called GeoSilex® which absorbs CO2; the paving was developed with the University of Granada and made entirely from industrial waste. The local newspaper referred to the park as "a new lung for the city."
      - Administrative, 2008-2009
        - Correspondence, 2008-2009 (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - Meeting minutes, 2008-2009 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - First design, 2006-2009
        - Competition, 2006 and undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Design, 2008 and undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - Design, Oct 2008 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - Drawings, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Redesign, 2009-2012
        - Campa, 2009-2012 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Kiosk, 2011 and undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - Photographs, existing site, Undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Torre Iberdrola, 2004-2008
      The winter garden functions as the lobby and reception area of the Iberdrola Tower. To enhance the character of the space, we selected three ancient olive trees. These trees, treated as sculptures, will emerge from a landscape composed by desert flowering plants.
      The public plaza around the tower has been designed over a submerged parking garage. This roof garden reads as the continuation of the surrounding landscape of the Campa de los Ingleses Park, also designed by Balmori Associates.
      The tower is LEED certified and all the water arriving to the site will be treated. There is a bioswale surrounding the tower to collect, filter and clean the water arriving to the site.
      - Administrative, correspondence, 2004 Jul (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Design, 2006-2008 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - The Garden that Climbs the Stairs, publicity, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      As a member of the jury for the second edition of an International Competition of urban gardens in the city of Bilbao called "Bilbao Jardín 2009", Diana Balmori was invited to create a temporary garden. Balmori, like each of the twenty-five selected participants, was assigned a ten meter by ten meter square in which to design a garden. The site was located at the landing of a large staircase between two Arata Isozaki towers leading to Santiago Calatrava's footbridge over the Nervión River.
      Instead of remaining at the landing of the stairs Balmori stretched the same hundred square meter surface into a narrow band and shifted the site in order for the garden to climb the stairs. In one broad stroke the garden performed a narrative of landscape which transformed the way this public corridor was perceived by users. In form, the garden engages the horizontal plaza with the rising vertical plane of the steps and the upright gesture of Eduardo Chillida's sculpture. Like the famous 'Spanish Steps' in Rome, the garden is not only designed for visitors to ascend and descend, but for them to linger.
      "The Garden That Climbs the Stairs" transformed a space in an unexpected way. It transformed the stairs and the space around them.
  - Farmington Canal Master Plan, 1941-2011, bulk 1987-2011
    The Farmington Canal, a 2-mile-long section of railroad in eastern Connecticut, has been abandoned since 1982. A canal that ran three miles through the city of New Haven and six miles through Hamden, a New Haven suburb, preceded the railroad. The masterplan for the Farmington canal reuse was initiated as part of the federal Rails-to-Trails rehabilitation program. Developed by Balmori Associates it sought, through substantial research, to reactivate the canal and transform it into a recreational corridor that connects disparate parts of the city with its center. By modest moves, the canal corridor can eventually affect projects that occur along it, becoming a spine on which to hang other built development.
    The two mile long Yale owned section sits by the new Engineering Research Building of Yale University, located at the corner of Prospect Street and Trumbull Street. Working together with its design architects, civil and environmental engineers, Balmori Associates explored numerous sustainable design ideas. The porous paving used as part of a larger storm water management strategy reduces runoff's volume and velocity.
    The section of abandoned railway is envisioned not simply as a trail but a new prototype of public open space, a linear park made up of discrete green segments that respond individually to their respective urban or suburban contexts.
    - Administrative, 1988-2002
      - Project directory, 1988-2001, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Yale guidelines, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Summary, 2000, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Memorandum, 1989-1992 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Strategy, Undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Proposal, 1989-1993 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Grants, 1988-1994
      - Design Advancement Project Grant, 1989-1990, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - NEA Grant (Hamden), 1989-1992 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - New Haven LIght Rail Design Study, 1988-1994 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Analysis and research, 1989-1994 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Design, 1990-1992
      - Meeting minutes, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Narrative and notes, 1991-1992, undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Drawings and sketches, 1990-1991, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Design study screen folder, 1991 Feb (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Budget, 1989 and undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Design disciplines, Balmori and Burch, 1993-1994 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition, Museum of Contemporary Art (MoCA), Los Angeles, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Publicity, 1987-2006
      - Press releases, 1988-2006 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Articles, 1987-1996 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Images, 1989-1993
      - Pictures, negatives, and slides, 1989, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Pictures, negatives, and slides, 1990-1993, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Transparencies, Undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Rail to trail, 1989-1991 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Pavers, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Board of Zoning appeals, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Dixwell Avenue streetscape, 1991-1992 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Farmington Canal video, 1994, undated
      - Master tape, Undated (Box 24)
      - Master tape, full length version, Undated (Box 25)
      - Master tape, deleted interview version, 1994 Dec 1 (Box 26)
    - Farmington Canal site visit video (edited version), 1993 (Box 27)
    - Farmington Canal Extension, 2006-2011
      - Project directory, Undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and punch lists, 2006-2011 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Addendum, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Schedules, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Notes, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Meetings, 2009-2010 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Certification, 2010-2011 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Approval, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Change order, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Project manual, 2010 Feb 16 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Submittals and shop drawings, 2005-2010 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Submittals, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 12-13)
      - Conceptual plan, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Farmington Canal Improvement, 1941-2010, bulk 1987-2010
      - Preliminary analysis, Old Campus, 1989, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Title sheet and drawing index, 2009 Dec 11 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Title sheet and drawing index, 2010 Feb-Mar (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Drawings, 2010 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Drawings, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Submittals, 2010 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Construction change directive, 2010 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Street maps, 1941-1971 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Yale Engineering Building, 1964-2010, bulk 2001-2010
      - Administrative, 1964-2010
        - Correspondence, 1988-2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Transmittals, 2003-2005 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Bulletin, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - LEED certification, 2004-2005 (Box 30, Folder 4)
        - Schedule, 2001-2002 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - Submittals, 2004-2005 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - RFI, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Meeting notes, 2002-2003 (Box 30, Folder 8)
        - Specifications, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Cost estimates, 2002-2010 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - Budget, 2003 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - Fee, 2003 and undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Proposal and scope, 2002-2004 (Box 30, Folder 13)
        - James Dwight Dana House, 1964-2003 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Design, 2002-2010
        - Drawings, 2002-2004 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        - Sketches, 2002-2010 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Planting, 2001-2006 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Prairie Waterway, 1992-1999
    For a new development in the suburb of Minneapolis, we proposed a drainage system with a dual purpose: provide drainage for the development of nearly 500 homes and create and function as a public space. Dubbed 'Park Place' by local residents, the 91-acre park has now become an integral part of the community, not only as a part of infrastructure, but also as a public amenity.
    A series of strategies are used to temporarily store excess water and mitigate the risks of flooding through a swale system, ponds and channels planted with grasses and sedges. It resolves environmentally the issue of frequent flooding in a flat plain-with a high water table and peak storm volumes-emptying in the Red River.
    The designed riparian system consists of a civic lawn on axis with the downtown area, flanked by playing fields, bike paths and pedestrian paths; glimpses of wildlife are provided by the wetlands associated with this urban waterway.
    - Summary and notes, 1994, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Project directory, 1993, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Memorandum, 1992-1993 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Contract, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Grant proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Schematic design, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - EAW and 404 permit application, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Outline and brainstorm, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Research, 1993, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Publicity, 1993-1995 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, 1994-1999 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Plans, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 13-14)
  - The University of Texas, 1994-2007
    - Master plan - booklet and draft diagram of traffic report, 1995-1996 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Directory, 1994-2007 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Administration
      - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Memorandum, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Agenda, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Construction schedule, 1993-1995 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Proposal/contract, 1994-1996 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Design
      - Drawings and sketches, Undated (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
      - Drawings, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Plantings
      - Guidelines and landscape guidelines drawings, parking garage studies, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - Planting lists and sketches, 1995-1998 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Publicity, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Photographs and slides, Undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Washington National Airport, 1990-1997
    - Administrative
      - Directory, 1992-1994 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Project overview, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1992-1997 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Site visit reports, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Memorandum, 1993-1997 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Construction package, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Terminal packages, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Proposal, 1992-1996 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Contract, 1990-1997 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - Invoice, 1992-1996 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Submittal, 1995-1997 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Design
      - Design development, 1991-1993 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Design review, 1994-1996 (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Shop drawings, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - Scheme, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - Sketches and drawings, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 16)
      - Paving, 1994-1996 (Box 34, Folder 17)
      - Planting, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 18)
      - Landscape color and finish submittal, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Photographs and slides, 1994-1996 (Box 34, Folder 20)
      Computer files
    - DCA communications, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - DCA communications, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - DCA Ramp A wall studies, Undated (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Botanical Research Institute of Texas, 1994-2012
    - Correspondence, 1994-2008 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Agenda (SD Materials), 2006-2007 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Agenda (DD conference calls), 2006-2008 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Proposal (details), 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Plant list, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - LEED (DD), 2006-2007 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 2006 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Publicity images, 2007 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Walls, 2007-2012 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Design development
      - Pricing, 2006-2010 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Sketches, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Drawings, 2007-2008 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - Sketches and drawings, 2006-2007 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Submittal drawings, 2008 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - 11th Street Bridge Park (Washington, D.C.), 2014
    - Administrative, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Feedback from advisor community, Undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Design, Undated (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Publicity, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Competition design, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Competition submission letter, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Competition progress report, 2014 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Research, Undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Brookfield (Brooklyn, NY), 2014
    - Master Plan
    - Hardscape layout plan, 2014 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Design development, Undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Sketches, Undated (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Schematic drawings, Undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Writings by Diana Balmori, 1970-2006; Series II
  - Inventory of writings, 1970-2004, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Articles
    - "How Women Lost Power and How Men Came to Govern," The Daily Bruin, newspaper of UCLA, 2 pages, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - With Robert Oppenheimer, "Family Clusters: Generational nucleation in nineteenth-century Argentina and Chile," Comparative Studies in Society and History: An international quarterly; Vol. 21, No.2, 231-259, 1979 April (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "The Arts and Crafts Garden," Tiller: a bimonthly devoted to the Arts and Crafts Movement, Vol. I, No.6, 17-27, 1983 July-August (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "George B. Post: The Process of Design and the New American Architectural Office (1868-1913)," JSAH XLVI:342-355, 342-355, 1987 December (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "Landscape vs. Architecture: Park De La Villette," Landscape Architecture, 2 pages, 1989 January (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "A Path in the City A Path in the Woods," Places, Vol. 6, No. 4, 50-67, 1990 summer (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Public Space and Public Life: Designing a Public Life," Modulus: Politics and Architecture, The Architectural Review at the University of Virginia, Vol. 21, 84-95, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "Redefining the Boundary, Defining the Modern," Progressive Architecture, 2 pages, 1991 August (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Architecture, Landscape and the Intermediate Structure: Eighteenth-Century Experiments in Mediation," Journal of the Society of Architectural Historians, Vol. L, No. I, 38-56, 1991 March (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - With Margaret Morton, "Homeless in New York," The Independent, 92-95, 1993 November 14 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - "Making Magic Carpets," Kew, Published by the Royal Botanic Gardens, 56, 1993 autumn (Box 13, Folder 12)